BIANCA MALKOČ

bnmalkoc@gmail.com (310) 984-4889 Los Angeles, CA Website LinkedIn

Summary: Human Geographer with 5+ years of qualitative and quantitative research experience in academic and applied settings. Transitioning to user research (UXR). In my time off, I enjoy making art, hiking, biking, surfing, and attempting Claire Saffitz's dessert recipes.

Research Skills: Interviews, ethnography, surveys, journey mapping, feminist research methodologies, and proficient fluency in Serbo-Croatian.

Tools: Dovetail, Qualtrics, SurveyMonkey, Google Forms, Zoom, NVivo, R, ArcGIS, HTML, Salesforce

EXPERIENCE

Tutor Feb 2022 - Present

Study Hut Tutoring - Rancho Palos Verdes, CA

 Provided guidance for students ages 10-18 with English, social studies, math, and science coursework

Graduate Researcher Sept 2018 - Dec 2020

Geography Department, University of Oregon - Eugene, OR

- Developed research project studying uncertainty among residents of an informal settlement in Accra, Ghana experiencing repetitive demolitions of their dwellings
- Conducted qualtitative fieldwork in Accra, including surveys, participatory drawing, and 20+ semi-structured interviews with the help of a local undergraduate assistant
- Transcribed interviews and analyzed interview data using thematic coding; conducted thorough literature review of academic articles, policy briefs, and news sources
- Summarized findings into an 85-paged thesis and presented at multiple conferences

AmeriCorps - National Red Cross Corps Member

Aug 2017 - July 2018

American Red Cross - Signall Hill, CA

- Formed and maintained partnerships with community stakeholders and coordinated with organizations to bring disaster preparedness education services to under-resourced communities across Los Angeles
- Created training resources and promotional materials for volunteer events
- Led planning for a fire-alarm-installation event in San Pedro, CA

Undergraduate Research Assistant

May 2014 - July 2016

Geography Department, UCLA - Los Angeles, CA

- Worked in a soils lab processing and analyzing samples for soil organic carbon and nitrogen content
- Conducted analysis of SOC/N content and spatial variance using cross correlation (co-kriging) in R
- Conducted fieldwork in Botswana collecting soil samples and recording vegetation coverage

EDUCATION

M.A. Geography

University of Oregon

University of California, Los Angeles

2016

2020

B.A. Geography/Environmental Studies